-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案
The Case Book Of Sherlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第五季 第五集
S5E05
噢...天哪
Oh, my dear.
最亲爱的
My dearest.
我警告过你 我说过
I warned you, I said,
千万不要走近悬崖
do not go to near the edge.
你为什么推我 Baron?
Why did you push me Baron?
我亲爱的太太 你是在做梦呢
Dear wife, you're dreaming.
不 你撒谎...撒谎
No.You're lying.
噢 我亲爱的
Oh, my darling.
显贵的主顾
The Illustrious Client
有什么激动人心的事吗 福尔摩斯?
Anything stirring Holmes?
我了解的就这么多
I know no more than this.
也许是一个自大的傻胖子
There may be some fatty self-important fool,
也许是一件生死攸关的事情
it may be a matter of life or death.
嗯 你同意会面了?
Mmm, you grant this interview?
我已经确认过了
I've already confirmed it.
对于这个人你有什么了解吗?
Do you know anything of the man?
只知道陆军上校James Damery爵士
Only that the name Colonel Sir James Damery
是一个家喻户晓的名字
is a household word in society.
我可以告诉你更多
I can tell you a little bit more than that.
他擅长处理棘手而微妙的事情
He has rather the reputation
因而名声在外
for arranging delicate matters,
这些事情是不为媒体所知
which are to be kept out of the papers.
他举世闻名 在外交方面天赋过人
He's a man of the world with a natural turn for diplomacy.
所以我们可以认为
And then, therefore to hope
这不是一个错误的警报
it is not a false scent,
他应该真的需要我们的帮助
that he has some real need of our assistance.
我们?
Our?
嗯 华生 要是你能好心帮帮忙的话
If you'll be so good Watson.
我很荣幸
I shall be honored.
那么在四点半以前
Then until four-thirty o'clock
我们可以暂时把这事抛在脑后了
we can put the matter out of our heads.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
这次我们要对付的是欧洲最危险的人
we are dealing on this occasion with the most dangerous man in Europe.
我曾经有几个对手
I've had several opponents
也可以被冠之以这样的称呼
to whom that flattering term has been applied.
他是一个暴徒
A man to whom violence is familiar
杀人不眨眼
and who will literally stick at nothing.
您不抽烟吗?
Do you smoke?
请原谅我抽烟
Excuse my pipe.
要是您说的这个人
But if your man is more dangerous
比已故的Moriarty教授还要危险
than the late Professor Moriarty,
那他就真值得会上一会了
he's indeed worth meeting.
他叫什么呢?
May I ask his name?
您听说过Baron Gruner吗?
Have you ever heard of Baron Gruner?
那个奥地利的杀人犯?
The Austrian murderer?
那么您已经把他列为杀人犯了?
So you've already sized him up as a murderer?
我们的业务就是关注欧洲大陆各种罪案
It is our business to follow the details of Continental crime.
在Splugen隘道那起所谓的事故中
I'm sure that he killed his wife
正是他杀了他的妻子
when that so called accident happened
对此我毫不怀疑 就像亲眼所见一般
at the Splugen Pass as if I'd seen him do it.
我还肯定
Just as I am certain
是他除掉了唯一的目击证人
that he disposed the only witness,
那个无辜的牧童
that innocent shepherd boy.
Baron Gruner现在在英国
Baron Gruner is now in England.
他听说他就住在Kingston附近?
Residing near Kingston I'm informed?
没错
That is so.
我想您应该
Might I also suppose
也听说过Merville将军的名字吧?
you will have heard of General Merville?
他以前是个风云人物
Khyber Pass fame.
是的
Indeed,
Merville将军有个女儿叫Violet
General Merville has a daughter, Violet.
年轻 富有 多才多艺
Young, rich, accomplished,
不管从哪方面看 都是个非凡的女孩儿
a wonder woman in every way.
她是个单纯的孩子
It is she an innocent
我们要努力把她从那个魔鬼手里救出来
we are endeavoring to save from the clutches of this fiend.
他控制着她吗?
He has some hold over her?
福尔摩斯先生 对女人最有力的控制就是...
The strongest of all where women are concerned, Mr. Holmes.
哈 爱情
Ah, love.
对极了
Exactly.
亲爱的 要是我娶了你
In marrying you, my darling,
我过去的罪恶就可以得到宽恕了
all my past sins shall be absolved.
你告诉我的那些并不是什么罪恶
These aren't sins you've told me of.
那些都是诽谤
These are slanders.
我的天使
My angel.
跟所有伟人一样 你当时被诱入歧途了
You were seduced, as are all great men.
然而我还是决定让你知道我的过去
Yet I am determined you shall know my history,
详详细细地
every part of it.
那样的话 当我步上圣坛
Thus shall I come to the altar
心境澄明
purified in soul and spirit
最终我才对得起你的爱 对吧?
and worthy at last of your love?
不过是六个星期
Just six weeks,
噢 Adelbert
Oh Adelbert.
我不能假装过去清白无暇
I cannot pretend my past is without stain.
没有一个出身贫困
No man born in poverty
而又白手起家的人可以那样说
who has created his own fortune
说实话吧 不是的
can say that and speak the truth, oh, no.
我曾经被迫做出不少无情的事情 亲爱的
I have been forced to many a ruthless act, my dear.
我该从哪儿说起呢?
Where shall I begin?
福尔摩斯先生 看到有人
To observe, Mr. Holmes, an atrocious event,
就在您眼前谋划着一起残忍的罪行
preparing itself before your very eyes
却无力改变它
and yet be powerless to avert it.
还有任何人面对过
Could anyone, any human being
比这更难受的事情吗?
be placed in a more trying position?
也许没有
Perhaps not.
那么您应该能够同情 我当事人的处境
Well then you will sympathize with the client in whose interest I am acting.
我不明白
I did not understand
您居然只是中间人
that you were merely an intermediary,
那谁是委托人呢?
who is the principal?
我恳求您不要问这个问题
I beg of you not to press that question.
他的名字不能被牵扯进来
His name cannot be dragged into this matter.
他的动机是非常高尚的
His motives are to the last degree honorable
但是他不想让别人知道
but he prefers to remain unknown.
而您的费用是不成问题 我可以保证 福尔摩斯先生
I need not say that your fees will be assured, Mr. Holmes.
而且您不会受到任何约束
And you will be allowed a free hand.
委托人的名字又有何相关呢?
Surely the actual name of your client is immaterial.
我只能拒绝您的要求了 James爵士 我很抱歉
I must decline to act, Sir James, I'm sorry.
我习惯了案件本身的迷雾重重
I'm accustomed to having mystery at one end of my cases
但连您这边也是 未免太让人困惑了
but to have it at both ends is too confusing.
不行
No.
您让我太为难了
You place me in the most serious dilemma.
福尔摩斯先生
Dare I say, Mr. Holmes,
我得说您没有意识到您这样做的后果
you hardly realize the affect of your own action.
我保证过
I have given my word
不泄露我当事人的名字
not to reveal the identity of my client.
能否允许我至少把可以讲的事 先告诉您?
May I at the least lay all I can before you?
您必须明白
It is understood.
我没有做出任何承诺
I commit myself to nothing.
那是当然 我明白
But of course, yes, yes.
画得太像了
A perfect likeness.
是谁画的?
Who painted it?
Innsbruck的Hans
Hans of Innsbruck,
他是雕刻家Claus的后代 以雕刻铜像而著称
a descendant of Claus the sculptor famous for his bronzes
就像这尊
such as this.
我将委托Hans来为你 画一幅肖像 我亲爱的
I shall commission Hans to attempt your likeness, my precious.
我爱这个房间
I love this room.
到处都有你的气息
It breathes of you.
这是什么呀?
What's this?
你的日记吗?
Your diary?
不 不 它是...
No, no, it is,
是我的日常记事本
it is my commonplace book.
里面记录着我看过的
In it I record things I've seen,
读过的和欣赏的东西
read, admired,
也许有时还有
occasionally perhaps
我的一点儿想法
a thought or two of my own.
但是它上了锁
But it's locked.
它代表我的一部分
It is a little part of me,
何况 我怕仆人会偷窥
besides a servant might pry.
有一天 也许...
One day, perhaps,
我们可以一起读一读
we shall look at it together.
不 我尊重你的隐私 亲爱的
No, I respect your privacy, my darling.
无论我们分享多少
We must all keep something of our own,
总该有一些自己保留的东西
however much else we share.
你真是太完美了
You are perfect.
你应该教我一些瓷器的知识 Adelbert
You must teach me about porcelain, Adelbert.
好的
I shall.
收藏是一大乐事
Collecting is such a pleasure,
赏心悦目
such a delight,
总能让我充满激情
it is a passion with me
就像你一样 我亲爱的
just as you are, my precious.
这个恶棍黏上了这位女士
The villain has attached himself to a lady
而且是彻彻底底
with such effect that he has completely
赢得了她的芳心
and absolutely won her heart.
对他不利的话她一句也不想听
She will not hear one word against him.
总而言之 她打算下个月就要嫁给他
To sum up, she proposes to marry him next month.
她已经成年了而且意志坚决
As she of age and has a will of iron
真不知道如何阻止她
that's hard to know how to prevent her.
这个被爱冲昏头脑的女士
Does the infatuated young woman
知道发生在瑞士的那件事情吗?
know of the Swiss episode?
这个狡诈的恶魔
The cunning devil
把他过去所有令人厌恶的丑事都告诉了她
has told her every unsavory scandal of his past life
可是总把自己说成是
but always in such a way
无辜的受害者
as to make himself out to be the innocent martyr.
她完全听信于他
She accepts his version
别人的话也不听
and will listen to no one,
连长辈们的话也听不进去
not even her fathers.
天哪 James爵士
Dear me, Sir James,
您是不是不小心泄露了 你的委托人的名字?
have you not inadvertently let out the name of your client?
将军吗?
The General?
噢 不 华生医生
Oh no, Dr. Watson,
那位坚强的军人受此打击 已经一蹶不振了
that strong soldier has been utterly demoralized by this incident.
MHudson太太
Mrs. Hudson.
您摁铃了吗 先生?
You rang, sir?
能不能麻烦你把这个 送到街角屠夫家的男孩那儿?
Will you deliver this to the butcher's boy around the corner?
那个一只眼睛长得很可笑的小坏蛋吗?
That young rascal with the funny eye?
另一只眼睛却是无价之宝啊 还有他的自行车
The other is invaluable, so is his bicycle.
好的 先生
Sir.
我该怎么联系您呢 James爵士?
How may I keep in touch with you, Sir James?
您接受我的委托了吗?
You accept my commission?
不妨说是您的问题引起了我的兴趣
Let us just say that your problem interests me.
通过Carlton俱乐部可以找到我
The Carlton Club will find me.
Baron在Kingston的具体地址是什么?
And the Baron's exact address in Kingston?
Vernon宅邸
Vernon Lodge,
一座大宅
the large house,
他是个有钱人
he's a rich man.
啊哈 投机者在成功的时候都是有钱人 James爵士
Uh-huh, speculators when successful frequently are, Sir James,
您还能提供
what further information
更多有关这个人的信息吗?
can you give us about the man?
他的嗜好所费不菲
He has expensive tastes.
收藏书籍 绘画
Collects books, pictures,
噢 还有中国瓷器
oh, and Chinese pottery.
他是这方面公认的权威
He's a recognized authority,
写过一本相关的书
written a book upon the subject.
James爵士 您可以告诉您的委托人
Well, Sir James, you may tell your client
我会开始注意Baron Gruner的
that I'm turning my attention towards Baron Gruner.
福尔摩斯先生 我毫不怀疑
I have no doubt, Mr. Holmes,
您不费吹灰之力就可以 追查出我的委托人的身份
you can easily trace my client.
但我必须请求您以名誉担保
But I must ask you as a point of honor
请您不要这样做
to refrain from doing so.
不要去挖出他的名字
Do not, I beg you, break in upon his incognito.
我想这点我可以保证
I think I can safely promise that.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见 医生
Dr. Watson.
你这是在浪费时间 华生
You're wasting your time, Watson.
Merville将军的生涯
Now the career of General Merville
也许正好帮我们查出我们委托人的身份
might well give us a pointer as to our client.
他是如此杰出
He's clearly illustrious.
但是您没有听到James爵士说的话吗?
But did you not hear, Sir James?
他要求的是你 福尔摩斯
His request was to you, Holmes.
这样做不光彩 华生 不光彩
But that is shameful, Watson, shameful
再说我们的脑子要用在更有价值的地方 打消这念头吧
besides our minds should be  more gainfully employed, desist.
对这件事你有什么看法吗?
Any views?
你没有吗?
Have you none?
还没有
Not yet.
只有一个想法 我已经着手行事了
Beyond the one I've already acted upon.
屠夫家的男孩
The butcher's boy.
这样做比发电报谨慎
More discreet than any telegraph.
嗯 我倒是觉得 你最好亲自去见见这位年轻女士
Well, I shall think you better see the young lady yourself.
从她入手
Start with her.
呃 要是那可怜的崩溃了的父亲 都不能说服她
Well, if her poor broken down father cannot move her,
我这样一个陌生人又怎能成功呢?
how can I, a complete stranger prevail?
呃 要是所有做法都不行
Well, if all else fails,
也许我会去的
Perhaps.
但是首先要利用下层社会
But first, the underworld.
因为他们能接触到犯罪的邪恶本质
For it is among the dark roots of crime
我们必须搜寻Gruner的秘密
that we must hunt for Gruner's secrets.
你已经派人去找Shinwell Johnson了 (福尔摩斯在伦敦黑社会里的一个耳目)
You've sent for Shinwell Johnson.
我有一个想法
I have but one insight,
Merville小姐也许能够宽恕谋杀
that Ms. Merville might well condone murder
但不会原谅某些更小的风流韵事
yet some smaller affair that might (unintelligible)
我们走着瞧吧
We shall see.
他们请到了最好的侦探
They have engaged the very best.
让他进来
Show him in.
这位是歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生  先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes, sir.
我早知道我们迟早会见面 福尔摩斯先生
I rather thought I should see you sooner or later, Mr. Holmes.
你肯定是受到了Merville将军的委托吧
You've been retained no doubt by General Merville
来阻止我和他女儿Violet的婚事
to prevent my marriage with his daughter, Violet?
是这样的吧?
That is so, is it not?
福尔摩斯先生 我竭力劝告您
Let me advise you very strongly, Mr. Holmes,
就此罢手
to draw off at once.
罢手?
Draw off?
亲爱的朋友
My dear man,
那不仅会毁掉你的好名声
you'll only ruin your well-deserved reputation.
在这件事情上 你是没有希望成功的 罢手吧 先生
This is not a case in which you  can possibly hope to succeed, draw off sir.
听上去有些奇怪 不过这也正是我要给你的忠告
It is curious but that is the very advice that I've come to give you.
我坦率地说了吧
Let me put it to you man to man.
如果你坚持要缔结这桩婚事
If you persist in this marriage,
你将会树起无数劲敌
you will raise such a swarm of powerful enemies,
到时连在英国的立足之地都没有
England would be too hot to hold you.
你就此罢手将会是更明智的做法
Surely you will be wiser to draw off.
原谅我的忍俊不禁 福尔摩斯先生
Excuse my amusement, Mr. Holmes,
手上没有牌
but it really is very funny
却想赌上一把 这实在太滑稽了
seeing you trying to play a hand with no cards in it.
连一张大牌都没有 先生
Not a color card there, sir,
除了小之又小的牌 你什么也没有
nothing but the smallest of the small.
你自以为
So you think.
不是'认为' 先生 是'知道'
So I know, sir, so I know.
让我明白地告诉你
Let me make the thing clear to you.
你觉得自己胜券在握
You consider your hand so strong
让我看见了也无妨吗?
that you could afford to show it?
当然了 因为事情是明摆着的
Certainly, since it becomes plain that in this instance
在这件事上你完全无能为力 福尔摩斯先生
you are clearly out of your depth, Mr. Holmes.
有没有可能你的能力被夸大了呢?
Could it be that your capabilities have been subject to hyperbole?
你的一手牌呢 给我看吧
Your hand, show it.
你不坐下来吗?
Won't you sit down?
我想还是不要了
I think I shan't.
那就随你的便
Please yourself.
呃 先生
Well, sir,
我碰巧就是很走运
it happens I have been fortunate enough
赢得了Merville小姐全心的爱
to win the entire affection of Ms. Merville.
尽管我曾经清楚地对她讲过
This in spite of the fact
过去发生在我身上的
that I have informed her clearly
所有那些不令人愉快的事件
of all the unhappy incidents in my past.
我还警告她说 某些耍阴谋的人会去找她
I have warned her that certain  designing persons would come to her.
我希望你认清这一点
I hope you recognize yourself in this
并把这些事情告诉她
and would tell her of these things.
我已经教过她如何来对付这些事情
I have instructed her how to treat them.
她对你的拜访已经做好准备了
She is well prepared for you.
她肯定会答应见你
She will no doubt give you an appointment
而且听完你的陈述
and she will listen.
但你的所作所为都是徒劳
It will be to no avail, however.
要是你想说些什么
If you wish to speak,
现在正是时候
now is your moment.
不
No,
还不到时候
this is not the moment.
顺便说一句 福尔摩斯先生
Oh, by the way, Mr. Holmes,
你认识法国侦探Labrun吗?
did you know the French Agent Labrun?
当然认识
Of course.
那你也知道他出了什么事情吧?
So you know what befell him?
他在巴黎的Lamont区遭到了毒打
He was beaten in the Lamont District of Paris
落下了终生残废
and crippled for life.
没错
Quite so.
奇怪的巧合是
By an odd coincidence
他之前同样在调查我
he had been inquiring into my affairs.
还是别那样做的好 福尔摩斯先生 那样做不吉利
Don't do it, Mr. Holmes, it's not a lucky thing.
我的最后忠告是...
My last word to you is
你走你的阳关道 我走我的独木桥吧
you go your way,let me go mine.
好自为之吧 Gruner
Mind you Gruner,
如果你指望为英国社交界所接受
because if you aspire to be accepted into English Society
你就要学会在点雪茄之前
you'll do well to remove the band
先把外头的标签去掉
from your Havana before lighting it
否则人家会把你当成一个暴发户而瞧不起你
otherwise you'll be put down for a bounder.
Hudson太太 福尔摩斯回来了吗?
Mrs. Hudson, has Holmes returned?
还没呢 先生 不过有两个客人在等着
Not yet, sir, but there are two visitors waiting.
谢谢 Hudson太太
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson.
啊 Johnson
Why Johnson.
晚上好 医生
Evening, Doctor,
福尔摩斯先生给我捎话了
Mr. Holmes sent word to me.
我知道 Johnson 我知道
I know, Johnson, I know.
我还把Kit带来了 因为...
And I brought Kit here because...
我在博物馆耽搁了一会儿
That's when I was delayed at the museum
然后又是交通
and then the traffic,
有辆马车在Great Russell街翻车了
an omnibus overturned on Great Russell Street,
他们得拖走两匹死马
two dead a horse had to be put down.
请原谅 先生们
Gentlemen forgive me,
我沉浸在自己的谜题中
I was absorbed by the mysteries of me,
而忘记了时间 女士
I quite forgotten the hour, madam.
这是Winter小姐 福尔摩斯先生
This is Ms. Winter, Mr. Holmes,
我们叫她Kitty
Kitty we call her
对于Gruner她没有什么不知道的
and what she don't know about Gruner.
当然了 请讲吧
Of course, please.
呃 Kitty自己可以讲
Well, Kitty can speak for herself.
不管怎么说 一接到您的口信
Anyway I put me hand right on her
一个钟头之内我就找到她了 先生
within an hour of your message, sir.
很容易就能找到我
I'm easy to find.
该死的 伦敦次次都让我犯迷糊
Hell, London gets me every time,
小胖也是
same address goes for Porky.
小胖? 那是你的外号吗 Johnson?
Porky, is that your nom-de-guerre Johnson?
你可从没说起过
You have never revealed that.
小胖 哈哈哈
Porky, well.
小胖和我是老相识了
We're old mates, Porky and me.
但是还有一个人 该下到比我们更深的地狱去
But there's someone who ought to be down in a lower hell than us
那个人就是你在调查的人  福尔摩斯先生
and that's the man you're after, Mr. Holmes.
我想我们能得到你帮助的吧 Winter小姐?
I gather we have your good wishes, Ms. Winter?
要是我能帮上忙让他露出原形
If I can help put him where he belongs,
我任您差遣 先生
I'm yours to the rattle, sir.
你知道他的企图
Do you know what he intends,
和目前的情况吗?
how the matter stands?
小胖说他又追上了某个可怜的傻瓜
Porky tells me he's after some other poor fool
只不过这次他想娶她
only this time he wants to marry her
而您想阻止他?
and you want to stop it?
是的
Yes.
您对这个恶棍肯定有足够的了解
Surely you know enough about this devil
去阻止任何头脑清醒的正派女子
to prevent any decent girl in her senses
陷入与他的纠葛之中
wanting to have anything to do with him.
可是她现在脑子并不清醒 Winter小姐
But she's not in her senses, Ms. Winter,
她狂热地爱着他
she's madly in love
而且她也听说过他的那些事了
and she has been told all about it.
可是她不在乎
She cares for nothing.
她也知道他杀过自己的妻子吗?
Told about the murder of his wife?
是的
Yes.
天哪 她肯定有很坚强的神经
My lord, she must have a nerve.
确实如此
She has.
您就不能把证据给她看吗?
Can't you lay proofs before her?
你能否帮我们这样做?
Can you help us do so?
我就是一个证据
I am proof,
活生生的证据
living proof.
要是我能站在她面前
If I was to stand before her
告诉她我是如何被他利用的就好了
and tell her how he used me.
你愿意吗?
Would you do this?
愿意
Would I,
难道会不愿意吗?
would I not.
也许值得一试
It might be worth the trying.
噢 不 他没有把全部都告诉她 先生
Oh no he didn't tell her all, sir.
全部?
All?
他收藏了我
He collected me,
他收藏女人
he collects women.
我是一个绘画模特
I was an artist's model,
一个受人尊敬的绘画模特
a respectable artist's model.
当然了 他书房里的那副肖像 就是以你为模特的
Of course, you sat for that painting in his study.
你去过Kingston了
You've been to Kingston,
那你也看过他的坛坛罐罐了
then you'll have seen all his crocks.
女人和瓷器
Women and china,
他酷爱的两样东西
they're his twin passions.
Gruner请别人画了这幅画
Gruner commissioned that painting
而之后
and afterwards,
之后...
and after...
呃 我们就这么说吧-- 在那之后我就再也无法工作了
well, let's just say I can never work again.
再也工作不了
Never.
再也...
我对你十分感谢 Winter小姐
I am exceedingly obliged to you, Ms. Winter,
我们会让你
we shall indeed interview you
跟Merville小姐见面的
and Ms. Merville together.
我的委托人会对你做出大方的补偿的
My client will compensate you most liberally.
噢 福尔摩斯先生 用不着的
Oh, none of that, Mr. Holmes.
我又不缺钱
I'm not out for money.
我就想看着这个人跌进泥潭
Just let me see this man in the mud,
让我给他的脸狠狠地踩上一脚
in the mud with my foot in his face
我就满足了
that's my price.
谢谢
Thank you.
来自Kingston的
From Kingston.
谢谢 Hudson太太 我不回复了
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson, no reply.
我们去吃饭吗?
Shall we dine?
可这是一封死亡威胁啊 福尔摩斯
This is a death threat, Holmes.
你还能指望Baron Gruner给我发来 什么更友善的东西吗?
Did you expect anything less from Baron Gruner.
福尔摩斯 还是小心为好
Holmes, have a care.
噢 华生 走吧
Oh, Watson, come along.
我们得吃东西了
We must eat.
快跑
Come on girl.
他们没有跟上来
They ain't following no more.
千万别这么想
Don't you believe it.
我说得没错吧
What'd I say.
你站到一边去 Kitty
Now you stand over there, Kitty,
这样才是个好女孩
there's a good girl.
好吧 谁先上 你吗? 还是你?
Right, who's first, you or you?
业余选手
Amateurs,
都是些生手
they've done no time,
什么也不懂 我们走吧
don't know nothing, come on girl.
有两个人想见您 先生
There's two persons wish to see you sir.
什么人?
Persons?
坦白地说 恐怕不能算是什么绅士
I couldn't in honesty term them gentlemen, sir.
我就来
I'll come.
他带着武器吗?
Was he armed?
没有 先生
No, sir.
到厨房里去
Go through to the kitchens,
把自己好好洗干净
clean yourselves up
然后走吧
and clear out.
我是出于对我父亲的尊敬
I have agreed to this visit
才同意与你会面的 福尔摩斯先生
out of respect for my father, Mr. Holmes,
这样做可不是为了你
rather than for you.
我的未婚夫对我说
My fianc?assures me
你已经不是原来的你了
you are no longer what you were,
有钱能使鬼推磨啊
a spent force.
而Winter小姐你...
And you, Ms. Winter,
你的出现应该是毫无必要的
surely you must also be superfluous.
我们完全是出于好意
Our intentions are the best.
我们是来帮你的
We are here to aid you.
是嘛?
Really?
你们到这儿来诽谤我的未婚夫 也算是好意吗?
When you call to malign my fianc?
Merville小姐 我不是以富有爱心而出名的
I am not renowned, Ms. Merville,  for the warmth of my affections
但我却能欣赏别人的爱心
but I can appreciate them in others.
如果我有个女儿
Had I a daughter,
我会为她着想的 就像将军为你那样
I should, I hope feel for you as the General does,
我们的关切也不是没有根据的
nor is our concern without foundation.
看来你已经开始在恶意中伤了
There, the slander begins.
非也 我并非那种会轻易上门拜访...
No, I do not readily call upon anyone
...并且去恳求别人的人
to beg or to plead
但事关Baron Gruner 请你认真听我说 我从来都不会毫无根据地乱说话
but in Baron Gruner, please, I never speak idly.
你选择了他 既不明智又很危险
You've chosen not only unwisely but dangerously.
Merville小姐
Marry him, Ms. Merville, and I assure you
根据我对犯罪心理的了解
with all the knowledge I have
如果你嫁给他
of the criminal mentality,
我敢说你将面临极大的危险
you will be in mortal danger.
会落得前男爵夫人那样的下场
Just as the former baroness was,
她也是太为他着迷
she too was infatuated,
以致付出了死亡的代价
and paid the fatal price,
用她的性命为他换来了一大笔财产
her life for a fortune.
满口谎言
That's a lie.
你应该注意到
You are of course aware
Splugen隘道
that the Splugen Pass
是连接意大利和瑞士的吧?
where your predecessor died
那就是他的前一任夫人死去的地方
runs between Italy and Switzerland?
这跟地理学又有什么关系?
What does the geography matter?
如果你打算把一个无助的女人
A great deal,
从一个国家境内的悬崖推下去
when you plan to hurl a helpless woman
而正好让她在另一个国家摔断脖子
off a cliff in one country
那地理学的关系可就大得很了
to break her neck in another.
但那只是一起意外
But it was an accident.
那为什么
Then why did the shepherd boy
那个目睹男爵夫人坠崖的牧童
who saw the baroness fall
会死于砒霜中毒呢?
die of arsenical poison?
谋杀他的女人便是受了Gruner的诱骗
His murderess whom Gruner had seduced
她在审讯时供认
confessed at her trial
是他威胁她去投毒的
that he'd obliged her to administer the fatal substance
不然的话
or risk disfigurement for life
他就会用硫酸将她毁容
by oil of vitriol.
这些都是事实 Merville小姐
Those are the facts, Ms. Merville.
我恳求你
I beg you,
想象一下
picture the awful situation
要是你在婚后
you will find yourself in
才对你未婚夫的本性有清醒的认识
if you only wake to your fianc?s true character
那情形将会是多么可怕
after you have married him.
我一直在很耐心地听你说话 福尔摩斯先生
I have listened to you with patience, Mr. Holmes.
我知道我未婚夫过去的生活颇为颠沛
I am aware my fianc? has had a stormy life
招致了许多非常不公平的中伤
in which he has incurred most unjust aspersions.
也许你的用意是好的
Possibly you mean well
尽管我知道你只不过 是人家花钱雇佣的侦探而已
though I learn you are a paid agent
但是不管怎么说我爱Baron Gruner
but in any case I love Baron Gruner
而他也爱我
and he loves me.
你已经向我介绍了这位女士的名字
You have told me this young lady's name
而且说她的到来是有原因的
and that there is a reason for her presence.
确实是有原因的
I'll say there is.
你到底是什么人 Winter小姐?
And what exactly are you, Ms. Winter?
我吗? 我来告诉你吧
Me, I'll tell you.
我来告诉你我是什么人
I'll tell you what I am.
我曾经是他的情妇
I was his mistress that's who,
是他上百个情妇中的一个
one of a hundred more.
他引诱我们 利用我们 毁掉我们 然后就把我们扔在一边
He's tempted, used, ruined and thrown aside,
他也会这样对你的
as he will you too.
得了吧
Please.
你要是嫁给他 你就完了
You marry this man it'll be the death of you.
你最后从他那里得到的 不是一颗破碎的心就是一个折了的脖子!
It may be a broken heart or a  broken neck but he'll have you.
噢 是嘛
Oh really.
你也许觉得你跟别人不一样 好了 Kitty
-You may think yourself different. -Thank you, Kitty,
你已经说得够清楚的了
you've made yourself admirably clear.
我知道 我未婚夫曾有三次
I'm aware of three occasions in my fianc?s life
被颇有心计的女人纠缠不休
when he has become entangled with designing women.
而他真心的悔悟已经使我放下心来
And I'm assured by him of his hearty repentance.
他?
Him?
他会悔悟?
Repent?
还说只有三个女人?
And only three?
噢 你这个傻瓜!
Oh, you fool,
你真是个愚蠢的傻瓜!
you stupid fool.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
我遵照我父亲的意愿与你见面
I have obeyed my father's wish in seeing you
但我不想被迫 去听这些话带诽谤的疯言疯语...
but I'm not compelled to listen to the slanderous ravings...
疯言疯语?
Ravings?
你说我疯言疯语!
Ravings!
哦 天哪
Oh my god,
我要让你看个明白
I'll show you.
看啊
Look,
look.
你看见了吗?
You see that?
这里 都是硫酸造成的
And here, oil of vitriol.
就是他干的
He did it.
没错 就是他干的
Oh, yes, he did it,
就是你的未婚夫干的好事
your fianc?
你骗人!
That's a lie.
你骗人! 好了  Kitty
-It's a lie. -Thank you, Kitty.
你可以告诉Baron 不把他绳之以法
You can tell the Baron that I shall not rest
我决不罢休
until I bring him to justice.
Winter小姐
Ms. Winter.
为什么呢 Kitty 到底怎么回事?
Why Kitty, why?
不 请别再问了 为什么Gruner会这样对你?
-No please. -Why did Gruner treat you so?
因为...
Because...
-不 我说不出口 福尔摩斯先生 -在这节骨眼上你一定要告诉我
-no, I can't tell you, Mr. Holmes. -You must at this instant.
你说他收藏女人
You said that he collects women,
是什么意思?
what did you mean by that?
他有一个本子
It's a book he has.
一个本子?
A book?
褐色皮面的 还上了锁
Brown leather with a lock
上面还有他的金色盾徽
and his coat of arms in gold on it.
不 我实在不该提起它
No, I can't speak of it.
他对他的女人都做了记录吗?
He keeps a record of his women?
我们都在那个本子里
We're all in there.
照片 姓名 每人的详细情况
Photographs, names, details,
有关我们的一切都在那里头
everything about us.
他要我念它们 在我和他...
He tried to make me read it while he...
不 我实在说不出口
oh, no, I can't.
当你拒绝的时候.....?
And when you refused?
他就开始发狂
He went berserk.
他跑出了房间
He ran out of the room.
我当时正要穿衣服
I was trying to dress,
他就跑回来了 手里还拿着那个瓶子
he come back in with this bottle.
我当时还半裸着身子
I was half-naked
他就把硫酸直接往我身上泼
and he threw it straight at me.
那个本子在哪里?
Where is this book?
-我不知道 -你想啊
-I don't know. -Think.
不 不
No, no.
在书房里还是在卧室里?
In the study in the bedroom?
那是一年多以前的事情了
It's more than a year since I was there.
那你可以记起来的 Kitty 想啊
Than you can remember Kitty think.
在书房里
In the study,
在写字台的后面
back of the bureau.
谢谢 Kitty 谢谢
Thank you, Kitty, thank you.
Winter小姐的伤疤 也打动不了Merville小姐吗?
Ms. Winter's scars could not move Ms. Merville?
她很震惊 但很快就平静了
She was shocked but recovered instantly.
天哪
Good heavens,
似乎太没人性了
it seems inhuman.
我承认 我心里多少有些想看 她和Gruner的好戏
I confess that part of me could wish her joy with Gruner.
在知道了这件事情后 还任由她被命运摆布吗?
Abandon her to her fate after all this?
当我把Merville小姐跟Kitty对比的时候
When I compare Ms. Merville with Kitty
我确实是这样想的
whose spirit is as fine
Kitty的身体是受到玷污了 可她的心灵还是纯洁的
as her body is blemished, yes.
你不会放弃这个案子了吧?
You wouldn't withdraw from the case?
不用担心 华生
Have no fear, Watson,
我对Merville小姐的厌恶 与我要让Gruner受挫的决心相比 算不了什么
my disgust with Ms. Merville counts as  nothing against my determination to foil Gruner.
有一件事情让我懊恼
One thing irks me,
那就是我初次与Kitty见面的时候
that I've not paid more regard
我没有多留意她的举止
to Kitty's deportment when we first met,
还有她头发的样式
the manner in which she dressed her hair.
啊 太晚了
Huh, it's late.
我们该走了
We must be gone.
我的诊所还有堆积如山的事情 要完成呢 福尔摩斯
I've got a mountain of work to do at the surgery Holmes
明早再见你了
so I'll see you in the morning.
那明天见
Until tomorrow then.
好啊 歇洛克.福尔摩斯 看我们怎么收拾你
All right, Sherlock Holmes, let's be having you.
啊 我知道是谁指使你们的
Ah and I can guess to whom I owe this pleasure.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯受到致命袭击! 看报看报!
Read all about it.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯受到致命袭击!
Murderous attack on Sherlock Holmes,
murderous attack on Sherlock Holmes,
看报看报!
read all about it.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯受到致命袭击!
Murderous attack on Sherlock Holmes,
看报看报!
read all about it,
read all about it.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯受到了致命袭击!
Murderous attack on Sherlock Holmes.
没事的 华生
It's all right, Watson,
别一副吓坏的样子
don't look so scared.
你不该说话的
You mustn't talk.
胡说 我得说话
Nonsense, I need to.
我该怎么做呢 福尔摩斯?
What can I do, Holmes?
肯定是那个该死的奥地利人
Of course it was that damned Austrian.
你发话吧
Give me the word
我马上去狠揍他一顿
and I'll go and thrash the hide off him.
我的好华生
Good old Watson,
不不不 不用的
no, no, no, no.
这两个人
Was it the same pair
是不是袭击Johnson和Winter小姐的那两个?
that attacked Johnson and Ms. Winter?
有一个也许是的
One may have been,
另一个嘛  我怀疑不是
the other I doubt it
不过这个想法提醒了我
but (unintelligible).
我们必须给Johnson捎个口信
We must send a note to Johnson.
让他给Kitty在市郊 找一处安静的安身之所
Tell him to find a quiet suburb for Kitty.
她必须呆在那里 直到危险过去
She should stay there until the danger has passed.
然后...
And then,
我们必须夸大我的伤势
then we must exaggerate my injuries.
没必要那样做
There's no need for that.
就算如此 我们也得给媒体来点轰动的消息
Even so we must lay it on thick for the press.
我也许活不过这个星期了
I might not live the week out,
脑震荡 说胡话
concussion, delirium,
你想怎么说都行
I don't care what would you like?
要让他们收到最沉重的消息
They must receive the gravest bulletins.
还有什么吗?
Anything more?
有的
Yes.
把我的烟斗和烟条放在桌子上
Put my pipe on the table and the tobacco slip.
你必须休息 不可以抽烟
You must rest not smoke.
好的 医生
Very well, Doctor.
噢 我最亲爱的
Oh my dearest
对我而言你一天比一天更让我珍爱
every day you become more precious to me.
怎么啦?
What is it?
就是...
It's just that,
你非去美国不可吗?
must you really go to America?
噢 亲爱的
Oh, my darling,
只不过是短途旅行罢了
it's only a short trip.
我在芝加哥有很重要的金融业务
I have important financial business,
和某些产权需要管理
certain interests to regulate in Chicago
不过我会很快回来的
but I shall be back so soon,
就一眨眼的工夫
in the twinkle of an eye.
晚报 先生
The late editions, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看过报纸了吗?
Have you seen the papers?
那可怜的福尔摩斯
That poor man Holmes,
一天不如一天
he sinks daily.
恐怕你不能指望我
I'm afraid you cannot expect me
对福尔摩斯先生和他的不幸
to have very much sympathy with Mr. Holmes
怀有什么同情心
and his misfortune.
嗯 得了脑炎
Mmm, encephalitis has set in.
你读了新闻吗?
Have you seen the news?
没有
No.
星期五Gruner 要坐Ruratania号去美国了
Gruner sales for America on the Ruratania on Friday.
震撼性的消息
News hits hard.
星期五 那意味着他将从利物浦出发
Friday, that means he sails from Liverpool
而不是从南安普顿出发
not from Southampton.
那个小流氓想摆脱我们
That little rascal means to get away from us
但是他逃不了
but he won't.
我发誓他逃不了
By the Lord Harry he won't.
华生 我需要你去做件事
Watson, I need you to do something for me.
尽管差遣
I'm here to be used.
那未来的24小时
Then spend the next 24 hours
你要深入钻研中国瓷器
in an intensive study of Chinese pottery.
哇 1368年到1390年
Wow, 1368-1390,
他睡了 先生
He's sleeping now, sir.
应该是吗啡的作用
That would be the morphine.
您不会熬通宵吧?
You won't let the lamp smoke, will you?
不 不会的 下面的门锁了吗?
No, no, no, you locked up below?
我刚才锁上了
I did that a while back,
附近可是有杀人凶手啊
there's murderous folk about.
没错 没错
True, true.
不要强迫自己太用功了 先生
Don't drive yourself too hard, sir,
否则明天早上你什么也干不了
you'll be good for nothing in the morning.
不会的 我就快好了
No, I shan't be long.
Hill Barton医生
Dr. Hill Barton,
半月街369号
369 Half Moon Street,
西区的上流社区啊 这人是谁?
Mayfair West, who's this?
是你
You.
我?
Me?
这就是你今晚要用的名字 Hill Barton
That is your name this evening, Dr. Hill Barton.
是嘛?
It is?
是的 而且你将会拜访Baron Gruner
Yes, and you'll call upon Baron Gruner
大概在八点半左右
about half past eight.
他那时会有空
He'll be disengaged.
我已经派人捎去口信 说你会去拜访他
I sent a note telling him that you'll call.
而且 你得带上这个
Also, that you're bringing this.
这可是真正的明朝青花瓷
It is the real eggshell of the Ming Dynasty.
完整的一套可是价值连城
The complete set would be worth a king's ransom.
你是一个收藏家
You are a collector.
这套瓷器到了你手里
The set has come your way.
你听说了Baron的爱好
You've heard of the Baron's interest
打算把它卖个好价钱
and an investor is selling at a price.
什么价钱?
What price?
要是你说它举世无双
We will not exaggerate
也并非夸大其词
if you say it would hardly matched in the world.
这碗是James爵士替我找来的
Sir James got it for me.
来自他的一个主顾的收藏品
It comes from a collection of his client.
或者我可以说
Or I could say that
应该由专家来估价
it should be valued by an expert.
噢 华生 你今天的脑子真是灵光啊
Oh, Watson, you scintillate today.
我建议由Sotheby或是Christie来鉴定
I suggest Sotheby's or Christie.
你肯定他会见我吗?
You're certain he'll see me?
当然了
Oh, yes, it's the collection mania
他对收藏有着疯狂的热爱
in its most acute form.
我还要问最后一个问题 福尔摩斯
One last question, Holmes.
为什么你要我冒充一个古董经纪人呢?
Why have you made me a broker in antiques?
为了赢得时间
To gain time,
得到像这样一套瓷器的机会
the opportunity to acquire the set such as this
也许会让Baron
may persuade the Baron
推迟去美国的行程
to postpone his visit to the United States.
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
简单的心理学罢了 华生
Elementary psychology, Watson?
去Kingston  司机
Kingston please driver.
很好
Very fine.
非常好
Very fine indeed.
你是说你有相应的一整套?
And you say you have a set to correspond?
我知道在英国只有一个可以与它相匹配
I know of only one in England to match it.
要是我问你是怎么得到这个的
Would it be indiscreet of me
会不会有些唐突?
if I were to ask how you obtained this?
从哪里得到的真有关系吗?
Does it really matter?
当然有关系了
Of course it matters
像这样珍贵的藏品 出处就意味着一切
with precious objects such as these provenance is all.
呃 你都看到了 这个可是真品
Well you can see the piece is genuine.
至于价值嘛...
As to the value I'm perfectly content
请专家来估价最好了
to take an expert's assessment.
我想你就是专家吧 Hill Barton医生
I had supposed you were an expert, Dr. Hill Barton.
我说的是中立方的估价
I meant an independent assessment.
当然可以了
Of course.
我最近刚得到了一些青瓷
I have some recently acquired pieces of celadon
你想看看吗?
you might care to view?
当然了
By all means.
请吧
Please.
完美无瑕
It's flawless.
典型的12世纪的宋代瓷器
Typical 12th Century Sung, I'd say,
你觉得呢?
wouldn't you?
你说得没错
You're right.
那这个呢?
And this?
我得说
That's an excellent example,
这是非常出色的秦朝瓷器
Ching Dynasty I should say
大概在公元265年
circa 265 A.D.
完全正确
Precisely.
那这些呢?
And these?
经典的青花瓷 对吧?
Typical of celadon would you say?
让我看看 让我看看
Give me time, give me time.
我会让你看的 先生
I am giving you time, sir.
没错
Quite so.
我想听听你对
I should also be interested in your views
明朝洪武年间瓷器上印记的看法
on the marks of the Hung Wu.
洪武瓷器的印记?
Marks of the Hung Wu?
这可是个争论不休的问题
That's a vexed question.
的确是个争论不休的问题 先生
Vexed question indeed, sir.
真正的洪武瓷器是没有印记的
There are no marks on the genuine Hung Wu.
真是让人难以忍受 先生
This is intolerable, sir.
我来这里是想给你点好处的
I came here to do you a favor,
而不是来做一个受拷问的学童
not to be examined as if I were a schoolboy.
你是来这儿侦查
You came here to spy.
不是的
Not so.
也许你觉得
You may have found it easy
撒个谎 伪装个身份
to inveigle your way in here
进入我的屋子很容易
upon false pretenses
但是我发誓 先生
but by god sir,
你会发现从这儿出去很难
you shall find it harder to get out.
把你的手举过头顶 华生医生
Raise your hands above your head, Dr. Watson.
怎么回事?
What's that?
福尔摩斯 你!
Holmes, you.
不许动
Don't move.
我会射穿你的脑袋
I shall shoot you through the head
而不是心脏
rather than the heart
然后我会告知警方
and inform the police
说我把你误认成盗贼了
I mistook you for a common burglar.
我以前也扮过小偷
That is a role that I've played before
而且还成功了
with some success.
毫无疑问 先生
Without any doubt, sir,
这是你最后一次演出了
this will be your last time.
-Baron! -Kitty!
恶有恶报
Be done by your debt.
医生 医生 救我 救我
Doctor, doctor, help me, help me.
打电话给Baron的医生
Telephone the Baron's physician
啊 James爵士
Ah, Sir James,
请原谅我这么晚来打扰
forgive me for summoning you at this late hour
但是事情紧急 你必须在苏格兰场 掺和进来之前 得到这个
but there's no time to be lost. You must have this before Scotland Yard bumbles in.
苏格兰场?
Scotland Yard?
Baron Gruner要指控我们 指控华生冒名顶替
Baron Gruner's laid a complaint against us, Watson as an impostor,
而我则是入室盗窃
myself as a burglar,
我们两个都是
we were both.
我转移了Gruner的注意力
I diverted Gruner's attention
而福尔摩斯则找到了那个
while Holmes procured that.
你必须把这个拿给Merville小姐看
You must show it to Ms. Merville,
她会发现自己只是上百个女人之一
she will find herself one among a hundred.
Baron Gruner跟他的女受害人之间
The account of what sports
所玩的游戏的记录
Baron Gruner enjoyed with his female victims
也许最终可以
may have perhaps at last
让Merville小姐睁开眼睛
open Ms. Merville's eyes.
你真是干得太妙了 福尔摩斯先生 太妙了
You've done wonders, Holmes, wonders.
除了Kitty Winter
Except for Kitty Winter.
华生解释吧 我得休息了
Watson explain, I must rest.
Winter小姐是Gruner以前的一个情妇
Ms. Winter is a former mistress of Gruner's,
她跟踪我到了Kingston
she followed me to Kingston,
身上藏了一瓶硫酸
concealed about her was a flask of vitriol.
她把硫酸都泼到Gruner身上了
Which she unleashed upon Gruner.
他的右手严重受伤
Severely damaging his right hand
还有他的脸
and parts of his face.
他将终身毁容
He will be disfigured for life.
但是如果这些伤
But surely if these injuries
像你描述的那么可怕
are as terrible as you described them
那我们的目的就达到了啊...
then our purpose is sufficiently gained...
她会更爱他
She'd love him the more
把他当成一个毁了容的殉道者
as a disfigured martyr.
我们应该毁掉的 是他的道德形象而不是他的容貌
It is his moral side not his physical which we have to destroy.
那个本子将会让她彻底清醒
That book will bring her down to earth
我想没有别的能做到这一点
and I knew nothing else that could.
都是他亲手写的
It's in his own handwriting,
她肯定认得出来
she cannot get past it.
福尔摩斯 我和我的委托人对您感激不尽
Neither my client nor myself can thank you enough, Holmes.
要是Winter小姐甚至是你本人
Should either Ms. Winter or even you yourself
被警方为难
be incommoded by the police
请马上打电话给我
do not hesitate to telephone me.
谢谢 James爵士
Thank you, Sir James,
不过说实在的
but to tell the truth,
我从未受到苏格兰场的骚扰
I rarely if ever find myself inconvenienced by Scotland Yard.
晚安
Good night.
我得谢谢你 华生
I would like to thank you too, Watson.
谢谢 James爵士
Thank you, Sir James.
噢 还有这个
Oh, by the way,
明朝的碗
Ming dish
对
by jove yes.
价值连城 我想
Worth a king's ransom I understand.
(英国皇室徽章)
***
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
福尔摩斯 我发现我们委托人的身份了
Holmes, I've discovered the identity of our client.
原来就是...
It's none other than the...
一位忠诚的朋友和一位古道热肠的绅士
A loyal friend and a chivalrous gentleman,
不管是现在还是将来
let that now and forever
我们知道这一点就够了
be enough for us.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com